<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iOS | Steven's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stevenlordiam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-07T23:22:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://stevenlordiam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Stevenlordiam]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[stevenlordiam@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New in Leet 1.3 for iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/20150909/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-09T19:41:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/whats-new-in-leet-1-dot-3-for-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=1028148007&amp;mt=8">Leet</a> is launched on the App Store, it has been popular among students looking for technical jobs. I received feedbacks everyday about the new feature request and five star ratings in the App Store, thank you very much.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So based on the most highly requested features, I introduce the 1.3 version of Leet, it has some great features you will love and will be available to upgrade in a few days.</p>

<p>First, browsing the coding problems by difficulty. Now you can tap the title in the problem list and choose the difficulty in the drop down menu.</p>

<p>Second, I have added the discussion section in the answer, now you can see other people&rsquo;s solution and compare them to yours. Cheers!</p>

<p>Third, you can now use a botton to review the answers in landscape mode, no rotation needed (but you can always rotate it, it&rsquo;s your call). Also, two finger pinch is supported in case you need to zoom in the answer section.</p>

<p>Last but not least, I used some magic to speed up the loading, now you can enjoy the super fast speed of this app when reviewing the coding problems.</p>

<p>Please rate it if you think <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=1028148007&amp;mt=8">Leet</a> is helpful, and recommend it to your friends, the more people using it, the better it can be. Also if you find any bug or have any advice, send me an email in this app. I appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Leet 1.2 for iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/20150825/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-25T22:01:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/introducing-leet-1-dot-2-for-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks for all your support for <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=1028148007&amp;mt=8">Leet</a>. I received many feedbacks and I had put all your feature request in my developing plan. So last weekend I spent one day developing some highly requested features.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First thing you would love, all solutions for Leetcode! After I launched this app, <a href="http://www.jiuzhang.com">Jiuzhang</a> contacted me and gave me credit to use their <a href="http://www.jiuzhang.com/solutions/">solutions</a>. So I wrote a web crawler in Python to get all the solutions. I also use &ldquo;Show/Hide Answer&rdquo; button in my app to show/hide the solutions, of course, codes are syntax highlighted.</p>

<p>Second, I have made reviewing the problems and answers easier by supporting landscape mode. You can now rotate your iPhone or iPad to review them in a much wider way.</p>

<p>Also, I have added notification for you to remind you to &ldquo;shua-ti&rdquo; everyday, now you will never miss a day to review leetcode problems.</p>

<p>Please rate it if you think <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=1028148007&amp;mt=8">Leet</a> is helpful. Also if you find any bug or have any advice, send me an email in this app. I appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New iOS App for Leetcode - Leet]]></title>
    <link href="http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/20150811/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T22:35:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/new-ios-app-for-leetcode-leet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I said in last blog, I have decided to develop a new iOS app for leetcode. I finished it in three days for the first version. After fixing some bugs and updated the UI for iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, I summited it to the App Store.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>You can see a demo as follow. Since it&rsquo;s the first version so it&rsquo;s pretty raw and needs further improvement. For instance, I haven&rsquo;t added the account login feature, and the UI needs more polish. I will solve these problems in the coming updates.</p>

<p> <img src="/images/blog_image/demo.gif"></p>

<p>I have hosted it on Github, maybe someday I will open source it.</p>

<p>Please download and try it yourself <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=1028148007&amp;mt=8">here</a>. I appreciate any advice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New iOS Side Menu Demo]]></title>
    <link href="http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/20150806/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-06T22:45:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://stevenlordiam.github.io/blog/a-new-ios-side-menu-demo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was developing an iOS app for leetcode, I found when displaying the content menu, <a href="https://github.com/romaonthego/RESideMenu">RESideMenu</a> is good at showing the parallax effect for iOS 7/8 app. So I decided to deploy it on my app. But when I was adding more <code>UIViewController</code> to it, it had a bug. You can find the detailed issue I posted <a href="https://github.com/romaonthego/RESideMenu/issues/252">here</a>.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>After some source code reading, I found the solution: creating a subclass of <code>UIViewController</code> instead of <code>RESideMenu</code> as the README of RESideMenu said. Because the new <code>UIViewController</code> will behave as a separate <code>View</code> rather than the RESideMenu behavior. So you cannot connect them.</p>

<p>Beside fixing this bug, I also add more view to this project. You can see a demo below.</p>

<p> <img src="/images/blog_image/SideMenu.gif"></p>

<p>I have open sourced this project as a fork of <a href="https://github.com/romaonthego/RESideMenu">RESideMenu</a> and you can find the source code on <a href="https://github.com/stevenlordiam/SideMenu">SideMenu</a>.</p>

<p>Please make pull request or submit an issue if you have any advice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
